ILGWU. Gus Tyler papers, 5780/096
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Gus Tyler papers
1956-1996
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Assistant President;
Tyler, Gus.
5780/096
32.78 cubic feet
32 linear feet
Records
Correspondence, subject files, articles, transcripts of broadcasts, photographs, and other materials dating from the end of the 1950s to 1996.
3674959
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Connie Bulkley
Date completed:
June 2011
EAD encoding:
Casey Westerman, 2003Cheryl Beredo, June 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Biographical / Historical
Gus Tyler, author, commentator, educator, political leader, and official, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU).
Gus Tyler was born in New York in 1911. He attended New York University on a scholarship in the early 1930s, where he became involved in left-wing political activities. After graduating in 1933, Tyler briefly worked as a writer for the Jewish Daily Forward. His sharp intellect and socialist politics caught the attention of ILGWU president David Dubinsky, who hired Tyler to work in the union's Education Department. Tyler left the ILG after a few years to work with the Socialist Party, but returned in the late 1930s. He held a number of positions in the union and in 1945 became Assistant President, which position he held until 1989. Tyler is the author of many articles and books on labor, labor history, economics, and other topics, and for many years has hosted his own radio program on station WEVD in New York. He has also served as an adjunct faculty member at a number of universities and colleges in the U.S., and worked with the ILGWU's successor union, UNITE, as an assistant to the president. Tyler died on June 3, 2011 in Sarasota, Florida.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, subject files, articles, transcripts of broadcasts, photographs, and other materials dating from the end of the 1950s to 1996.
Individuals represented in the correspondence include: Mortimer Adler; William Brennan; Sol Chaikin; David Dinkins; David Dubinsky; Henry Foner; Moe Foner; Philip Foner; Jesse Jackson; Jay Lovestone; Jay Mazur; Bill Moyers; Jack Sheinkman; and Paul Volcker.
Organizations included in the correspondence and subject files include: the AFL-CIO; the American Veterans Committee; the Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies; the Brookings Institution; Histadrut; the Institute for the Future; the National Endowment for the Humanities; conventions, locals and departments of the ILGWU; various committees of the U.S. House and Senate; Workmen's Circle; WEVD (radio station, New York); WNET (Channel 13, New York); and the World Veterans Federation.
Subjects addressed include: economic policy and conditions in the U.S.; international politics; the labor movement in the U.S. and abroad; employment of minorities; multinational corporations; politics and government in the U.S., especially in New York City and State; social conditions in the U.S.; veterans' affairs; and worker training and education.
Series I consists of both ILGWU and non-union correspondence. Series II is made up of subject files, dealing with both union and non-union matters. Series III contains publications, writings, transcripts of radio and television broadcasts, and other materials. Series IV consists of miscellaneous materials, including photographs, cassette tapes, and ILGWU publications.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU records
5780/052. ILGWU. Gus Tyler papers
5780/088. ILGWU. Gus Tyler papers
General
"Permanent deposit"
Arrangement
Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States.; International business enterprises.; International trade.; Labor union locals.; Labor unions--Officials and employees.; Labor unions--United States.; Labor unions.; Labor movement--United States.; Labor movement.; Minorities--Employment--United States.; Veterans--United States.; Veterans.; Working class--Education--United States.; World politics.; United States--Social conditions--1945-; United States--Economic conditions--1945-; United States--Economic policy--1961-1971.; United States--Economic policy--1971-1981.; United States--Economic policy--1981-1983.; United States--Politics and government--1945-1989.; New York (State)--Politics and government--1951-; New York (N.Y.)--Politics and government--1951-; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; Adler, Mortimer Jerome, 1902-2001.; Brennan, William J.(William Joseph), 1906-1997.; Chaikin, Sol C.; Dinkins, David N.; Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982.; Foner, Henry.; Foner, Moe, 1915-; Foner, Philip Sheldon, 1910-1994.; Jackson, Jesse, 1941-; Lovestone, Jay.; Mazur, Jay.; McCarthy, Eugene J., 1916-2005.; Moyers, Bill D.; Sheinkman, Jacob.; Tyler, Gus.; Tyler, Gus.; Volker, Paul A.; AFL-CIO.; American Veterans Committee.; Brookings Institution.; Histadrut ha-kelalit shel ha-'ovdim be-Erets-Yiśra'el.; Institute for the Future.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Convention.; National Endowment for the Humanities.; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees.; WEVD (Radio station: New York, N.Y.); WNET (Television station: New York, N.Y.); Workmen's Circle/Arbeter Ring.; World Veterans Federation.
3674959
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Correspondence. A-General, 1988-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence. Abram, Morris B., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence. Abrams, Robert, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence. Adelphi University, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence. Adler, Mortimer J., 1985-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence. African American Labor Center, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence. Allied Educational Foundation, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence. Altes, Jane, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence. Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence. American Committee on Italian Migration, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence. American Ditchley Foundation, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence. American Foundation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1988- 1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence. American Institute for Free Labor Development, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence. Americans for Democratic Action, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence. Anniversary of ILGWU, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence. ARCO Transportation Corporation [folder 1 of 2], 1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence. ARCO Transportation Corporation [folder 2 of 2], 1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence. Armstrong, Meg, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence. Asian Workers, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence. Association for Diplomatic Studies and Training, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence. Association for Union Democracy, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence. The Association of Governing Boards of Universities and Colleges, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence. B- General, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence. Backer, Florence. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence. Beder, Bernard, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence. Bellush, Bernard, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence. Bender, Jim, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence. Berkenwald, Issie (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence. Berry, John W., 1993 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence. Bicentennial for AFL-CIO, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence. Black Economic Study Project [folder 1 of 3], 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence. Black Economic Study Project [folder 2 of 3], 1988 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence. Black Economic Study Project [folder 3 of 3], 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence. Bonham, George, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence. Bookbinder, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence. Bradley, Bill, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence. Bradshaw, Thorton, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence. Bramucci, Ray, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence. Brennan, William J., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence. Briones, Michelle, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence. Brockway, George P., 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence. The Brookings Institute [folder 1 of 2], 1989 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence. The Brookings Institute [folder 2 of 2], 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence. Brower, Brock, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence. Brown, Alvin, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence. Buchsbaum, Susan, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence. The Business Agent Institute [folder 1 of 3], 1989 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence. The Business Agent Institute [folder 2 of 3], 1989 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence. The Business Agent Institute [folder 3 of 3], 1989 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence. Calendar 1987, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence. Calendar 1988 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence. Calendar 1990 [folder 1 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence. Calendar 1990 [folder 2 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence. Calendar 1991 [folder 1 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence. Calendar 1991 [folder 2 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence. Calendar 1992 [folder 1 of 2], 1993 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence. Calendar 1992 [folder 2 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence. Calendar 1993 [folder 1 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence. Calendar 1993 [folder 2 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence. Canadian Region, ILGWU, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence. Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence. Centennial Event, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence. Center for Adult Life and Learning, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Correspondence. Center for International Leadership, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Chaiken, Sol C. [folder 1 of 2], 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Chaiken, Sol C. [folder 2 of 2], 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Chaiken, Sol C. Article [folder 1 of 2], 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chaiken, Sol C. Article [folder 2 of 2], 1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence. Challenge Magazine, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence. Channel 13 WNET [folder 1 of 3], 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence. Channel 13 WNET [folder 2 of 3], 1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence. Channel 13 WNET [folder 3 of 3], 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence. Charleston Higher Education Consortium, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence. Chautauqua Institution [folder 1 of 2], 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence. Chautauqua Institution [folder 2 of 2], 1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence. Chicago Bar Association, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence. Christian Science Monitor, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence. City College of New York, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence. Cogen, Charles, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence. Collester, J. Bryan, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence. Continental Insurance [folder 1 of 2], 1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence. Continental Insurance [folder 2 of 2], 1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence. Continental Insurance Seminar 1990 [folder 1 of 4] (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence. Continental Insurance Seminar 1990 [folder 2 of 4] (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence. Continental Insurance Seminar 1990 [folder 3 of 4] (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence. Continental Insurance Seminar 1990 [folder 4 of 4] (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence. 35th Convention, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence. Convention 1995 [folder 1 of 7] (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence. Convention 1995 [folder 2 of 7] (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence. Convention 1995 [folder 3 of 7] (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence. Convention 1995 [folder 4 of 7] (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence. Convention 1995 [folder 5 of 7] (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence. Convention 1995 [folder 6 of 7] (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence. Convention 1995 [folder 7 of 7] (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence. Cooper, Milton (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence. Cornell University- Catherwood Library, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence. Corporate Planners, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence. Council on Foreign Relations, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence. Cowell, Susan [folder 1 of 2], 1988 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence. Cowell, Susan [folder 2 of 2], 1987 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence. Carver, Ken, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence. Danish, Keith, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence. Delegate Selection, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence. Delphi International Education and Training, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence. Delphi Research Association, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence. Denaro, John (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence. Dennis, Don, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence. Department of International Relations, ILGWU, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence. Department Personnel, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence. Dickerson, Kenneth (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence. Dictionary of American Biography, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence. Diebold Institute for Public Policy Studies, Inc., 1993 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence. Di Napoli, Thomas, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence. Dinkins, David [folder 1 of 3], 1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence. Dinkins, David [folder 2 of 3], 1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence. Dinkins, David [folder 3 of 3], 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence. Douglas, William, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence. Driscoll, Phillip (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence. Dubinsky, David. Labor Hall of Fame [folder 1 of 3], 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence. Dubinsky, David. Labor Hall of Fame [folder 2 of 3], 1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence. Dubinsky, David. Labor Hall of Fame [folder 3 of 3], 1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence. Dubrow, Evelyn, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence. Durand, Albert, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence. Eckstein, Bernard H., 1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence. Education Committee, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence. Education Department [folder 1 of 2], 1969-1983 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence. Education Department [folder 2 of 2], 1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence. Educational Directors [folder 1 of 2], 1980 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence. Educational Directors [folder 2 of 2], 1980 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence. Educational Task Force Committee [folder 1 of 7], 1988 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence. Educational Task Force Committee [folder 2 of 7], 1987 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence. Educational Task Force Committee [folder 3 of 7], 1987 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence. Educational Task Force Committee [folder 4 of 7], 1987 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence. Educational Task Force Committee [folder 5 of 7], 1987 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence. Educational Task Force Committee [folder 6 of 7], 1987 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence. Educational Task Force Committee [folder 7 of 7], 1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence. Eisenhower Exchange Fellowship, Inc. [folder 1 of 2], 1982 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence. Eisenhower Exchange Fellowship, Inc. [folder 2 of 2], 1973-1980 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence. Elias, Eli (Box 3)
  - Correspondence. Elmer, Fred, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence. Empire State College, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence. Encyclopedia Brittanica, Inc., 1992 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence. Epstein, Joseph, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence. Everitt, Alice L., 1992 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence. Farber, Harry L., 1992 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence. Figueroa, Sonia, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence. Florence V. Burden Foundation, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence. Foner, Henry, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence. Foreign Service Institute, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence. "The Forward" Staff, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence. Foundation for the Study of Independent Social Ideas, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence. Friends of the Department of Labor, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council [folder 1 of 2], 1985 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council [folder 2 of 2], 1985 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council [folder 1 of 3], 1987 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council [folder 2 of 3], 1987 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council [folder 3 of 3], 1987 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council [folder 1 of 8], 1988 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council [folder 2 of 8], 1988 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council [folder 3 of 8], 1988 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council [folder 4 of 8], 1988 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council [folder 5 of 8], 1988 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council [folder 6 of 8], 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council [folder 7 of 8], 1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council [folder 8 of 8], 1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence. General Advisory Council, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence. The George Meany Memorial Archives, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence. Gerendasy, Carrie, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence. Gewen, Barry, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence. Gibrick, Seymour, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence. Global Interdependence Conference, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence. Goldring, Robert, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence. Goodman, David L., 1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence. Gorham, Janet B., 1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence. Gotbaum, Victor (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence. Gottlieb, William P., 1980 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence. Grant Search Update, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence. Grills, Joe, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence. Halstedt, Steven C., 1991 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence. Harris, Lou, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence. Harrison, Gilbert, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence. Hazelrigg, Charles R., 1986 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence. Hazelrigg Conference, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence. Hazelrigg Conference [folder 1 of 4], 1986 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence. Hazelrigg Conference [folder 2 of 4], 1986 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence. Hazelrigg Conference [folder 3 of 4], 1986 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence. Hazelrigg Conference [folder 4 of 4], 1986 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence. Health Project [folder 1 of 4], 1986 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence. Health Project [folder 2 of 4], 1986 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence. Health Project [folder 3 of 4], 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence. Health Project [folder 4 of 4], 1984 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence. Heller, Ben, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence. Hernandez, Aileen C., 1987 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence. Higgins, George, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence. Hispanic Policy Development Project, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence. History of ILGWU, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence. Hofstra University, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence. Hong-Koo, Lee, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence. Horan, Hume, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence. Hufstedler, Kaus and Ettinger, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence. Hyde, Harry, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence. Ianni, Francis, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 40)